<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-01-03T22:51:27+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sakshi Sangwan</title><subtitle>Jotting down the thoughts and events.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Getting Stuck is my Forte</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/getting-stuck-is-my-forte/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting Stuck is my Forte" /><published>2020-01-03T22:48:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-01-03T22:48:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/getting-stuck-is-my-forte</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/getting-stuck-is-my-forte/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;getting-stuck-is-my-forte-o&quot;&gt;Getting Stuck is my Forte \o/&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am so excited to write this blog, probably because this is the state where I am usually found, &lt;strong&gt;stuck&lt;/strong&gt;. If you see me crying in a corner, I am in this afore mentioned state with the why’s and how’s. This is a part of my daily routine and thus couldn’t be separated from my Outreachy project as well. :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been stuck on most of the tasks at most of the steps, I would love to share the one that was simplest and yet took me a lot of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;task&quot;&gt;Task&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Update Debian’s wiki for Gitlab with the latest package.json at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.debian.org/Javascript/Nodejs/Tasks/gitlab&quot;&gt;https://wiki.debian.org/Javascript/Nodejs/Tasks/gitlab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Details&lt;/strong&gt;
 https://wiki.debian.org/Javascript/Nodejs/Tasks/gitlab should not be manually updated, rather it contains a  &lt;a href=&quot;https://salsa.debian.org/js-team/js-task-wiki-edit&quot;&gt;script&lt;/a&gt; to generate the page. The python script  &lt;a href=&quot;https://salsa.debian.org/js-team/js-task-wiki-edit/blob/master/js_task_edit.py&quot; title=&quot;js_task_edit.py&quot;&gt;js_task_edit.py&lt;/a&gt; takes in a file as an input and recursively fetches the dependencies of each mentioned package. It uses the tree module to create a dependency tree for the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I had to parse Gitlab’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab/blob/master/package.json&quot; title=&quot;package.json&quot;&gt;package.json&lt;/a&gt; to this script.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was unable to figure out how to do the same. It took me hours of random hit and trials and asking folks around how to go about it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I cloned the above repository, passed the path to the package.json while running the python script. It didn’t work, probably wasn’t able to trace back to the path &lt;em&gt;(that’s what I thought, apparently not true)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I copied the package.json to the same directory as the script and passed the file as an argument. It still didn’t work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It was pretty simple to do though, all that had to be done was run
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;python js_task_edit.py -f package.json&lt;/code&gt; and the -f flag was what I was missing all this while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took hours &lt;em&gt;(my laptop died twice while running it)&lt;/em&gt; for the final output to return since there are way too many package dependencies &lt;em&gt;(slow internet also seems a reasonable reason)&lt;/em&gt;. There’s still a pending task left here, I need to update the script to fetch dependencies up to 2-3 levels only. I have been trying a few ways that don’t seem to have worked up till now. (I’ll write more about it when I seem to have some progress there)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It more than often happens that one gets stuck in simplest of things, gives it hours and reach no where, mostly giving up on the whole situation itself. I realised it’s rather better to ask someone or take your mind off from the whole deadlock itself for a while. I am often scared to ask simple questions wondering that I might seem stupid, but the thing is it can save you hours and one might guide you in the right direction when you are running in the exact opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy hacking!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sakshisangwan</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="outreachy" /><category term="debian" /><summary type="html">Getting Stuck is my Forte \o/</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Beginning of a New Journey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-beginning-of-a-new-journey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Beginning of a New Journey" /><published>2020-01-03T03:20:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-01-03T03:20:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-beginning-of-a-new-journey</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-beginning-of-a-new-journey/">&lt;p&gt;The world of Free Software is pretty intimidating, at least that’s what I have felt since my very first encounter with those 
words itself. In whatever way you plan to contribute whether technical or non-technical, everyone around is going to notice that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most of the time, I thought about starting to contribute but it always ended with what, where and how; plus realising that I 
probably don’t know enough was such a bummer. Also, the fear of picking up even the smallest of tasks with such experienced and 
knowledgeable people around is super scary (even today).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gradually crawled into the Debian community(was probably dragged) with great support from a few friends, the baby steps led me 
to interning with the very same community under Outreachy. No, it wasn’t a one go process for me, everything I knew about FOSS and 
Outreachy had built a hefty amount of fear within me. So, the first time I planned to apply for Outreachy all I could do was create 
an account, that’s it, end of it. The second time, I went a step ahead and filled up the initial application form, which got accepted 
within 24 hours and then I went through the projects, read about them all, saw the requirements and just couldn’t figure out where 
to apply, it all felt huge and beyond my scope and that’s about it. This term was the third time I applied for it, filled up the 
initial application and went for Debian’s project “Packaging GitLab’s JS Modules”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did was to send an introductory email to the mentors (Utkarsh Gupta, Sruthi Chandran, Pirate Praveen and Xavier 
(yadd)), and went through the initial tasks. Soon that introductory email turned into a FAQ thread, about how to go about things what 
to do, getting stuck on stuff and finding help regarding those, and some great documents/ resources to go through; with all that 
hustle I was able to complete the initial tasks and communicate with the mentors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you remember the first line of this blog? Well all of it is still intimidating and I still am scared of everything but the good 
part is everyone here helps you out to lessen that fear. Whenever I was stuck I could just email my mentors and there they were 
happily helping with even the simplest of things. I am so glad that I finally applied, it has been quite a journey from using Debian 
to starting to contribute to it, I haven’t gotten any far up till now, but I am trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winding it up, I would say if you are sailing in the same boat of dilemma and fear, I believe you just need to start talking to people, 
there won’t ever be the right time where you could say you know enough, or it would all feel easy; but I am sure you’ll find so many 
people who will be willing to help you and guide you through all of it. With that in my mind, I am really thankful to Outreachy and 
all of my mentors. :D&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sakshisangwan</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="outreachy" /><category term="debian" /><summary type="html">The world of Free Software is pretty intimidating, at least that’s what I have felt since my very first encounter with those words itself. In whatever way you plan to contribute whether technical or non-technical, everyone around is going to notice that.</summary></entry></feed>